<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Benjamin Parry]]></title>
  <link href="http://benjaminparry.github.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://benjaminparry.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-09-29T12:24:12+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://benjaminparry.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Benjamin Parry]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Barcamp Brighton 7 Test Post proper]]></title>
    <link href="http://benjaminparry.github.com/blog/2012/09/29/barcamp-brighton-7-test-post-proper/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-29T12:22:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://benjaminparry.github.com/blog/2012/09/29/barcamp-brighton-7-test-post-proper</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Ahoy hoy!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Starcatching Supernova bookmarking]]></title>
    <link href="http://benjaminparry.github.com/blog/2012/09/24/starcatching-supernova-bookmarking/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-24T19:41:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://benjaminparry.github.com/blog/2012/09/24/starcatching-supernova-bookmarking</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>This is part of a talk I will be giving at <a href="http://2012.barcampbrighton.org/" title="BarCampBrighton 7 homepage">BarCampBrighton 7</a> <strong>My attempt at the perfect read-later workflow</strong></p></blockquote>

<p>I was one of the Delicious refugees of 2011 that ended up making a happy home at <a href="pinboard.in/" title="Social Bookmarking for Introverts">pinboard.in</a>. I was pretty rubbish at keeping up with tagging then and still pretty rubbish now, although Pinboard offer a superbly simple UI and cracking bookmarklet that makes light work adding new bookmarks and suggested tags.</p>

<p>Frank Chimero’s excellent talk <a href="http://2011.dconstruct.org/conference/frank-chimero" title="Frank Chimero’s Oh God, It’s Full of Stars audio from dConstruct 2011">Oh God, It’s Full of Stars</a> is a fascinating inward look at why we bookmark and what we do that data afterward. Ever since listening to it I&#8217;ve been concerned with mastering an automated workflow that adds as much useful sorting/retrieval data to those bookmarks, and, if possible, does something with it meaningful with it too.</p>

<h2>Case study: Twitter</h2>

<p>I favorite a hell of a lot of Tweets. Twitter don&#8217;t provide a decent enough solution to filter them, something only <a href="http://faavorite.com/" title="Twitter favorite managing app">faavorite.com</a> does well. Pinboard has a baked-in Twitter sync that pulls in links from your favorite Tweets. Initially I enabled it but thought there was more data that could be squeezed into the bookmark.</p>

<h3>Putting the internet to work for me</h3>

<p><a href="https://ifttt.com/" title="IFTTT homepage">If This Then That</a> is an amazing service that bridges the API gap between online services like Pinboard and Twitter and turned out to provide me with exactly the right kind of customization I wanted over my Twitter bookmarks.</p>

<p>There&#8217;s a few different reasons why I might want to favorite a Tweet:</p>

<ol>
<li>URL to interesting resource or article</li>
<li>Memorable or funny quote</li>
<li>Interesting conversation between 2 or more users</li>
</ol>


<p>So for an ideal bookmark entry it must have:</p>

<ol>
<li>URL included in the Tweet as the default bookmark URL</li>
<li>URL to the Tweet itself if the Tweet itself is the bookmark and the entire Tweet text</li>
<li>@ Twitter handle of the user</li>
</ol>


<p><em>As a bonus, related hashtags auto imported as tags</em></p>

<h3><a href="https://ifttt.com/recipes/58634" title="Favorite Tweet and add new Pinboard bookmark">☆ Twitter ☆ > Pinboard</a></h3>

<p>So I created a recipe that does just that, and more.</p>

<p>Currently, every time I favorite a Tweet the recipe is triggered and I get a bookmark that includes:</p>

<ol>
<li>Hyperlink to the first URL in the Tweet with it&#8217;s page title</li>
<li>Copy of the entire Tweet in the description</li>
<li>Hyperlink to the Twitter user</li>
<li>Hyperlink to the Tweet status</li>
<li>Tagged with custom identifier for filtering all Twitter favorites -  ☆twitter☆</li>
<li>Tagged with user&#8217;s @ Twitter handle for filtering</li>
</ol>


<p>This gives me a few options when coming back to retrieve a bookmarked URL, either I have a fair idea who&#8217;s Tweeted it or what text was included in the Tweet, both of which can be easily filtered through Pinboard&#8217;s powerful search.</p>

<p>I must admit pulling in hashtags as bookmark tags would be a huge advantage and unfortunately the URLs in the Tweet copy remain encrypted in Twitter&#8217;s t.co style which is very frustrating.</p>

<p>Even more annoying is that IFTTT now has to shut off most of their Twitter services after Twitter announced their recent API re-write. It&#8217;s a huge blow for a whole spectrum of users, one that might have <a href="https://join.app.net/" title="Developer focused, add-free social network">app.net</a> opening their doors wide. They already have IFTTT support so it just need that mass exodus like back in 2011.</p>

<h3>A galaxy of Likes</h3>

<p>The idea is to apply this method to every site that offers a favorite, Like or do-later operation, trying to squeeze as much additional data into the bookmark and improve the options for retrieval to close the loop.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Optimizing Octopress for Instapaper and Twitter]]></title>
    <link href="http://benjaminparry.github.com/blog/2012/09/23/optimizing-octopress-for-instapaper-and-twitter/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-23T18:48:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://benjaminparry.github.com/blog/2012/09/23/optimizing-octopress-for-instapaper-and-twitter</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>This is part of a talk I will be giving at <a href="http://2012.barcampbrighton.org/" title="BarCampBrighton 7 homepage">BarCampBrighton 7</a> <strong>My attempt at the perfect read-later workflow</strong></p></blockquote>

<p>For a while I&#8217;ve been obsessed with nailing a perfect read-later workflow for online publishing. I use Instapaper a lot and do most of my reading, distraction-free, on my 3rd gen. Kindle. I joined <a href="ifttt.com/" title="If This Then That">IFTTT</a> while in Beta and been using it as the missing link in this workflow. Lastly, my social media of choice is Twitter…<em>for now anyway</em>.</p>

<p>The aim of this workflow is to automate the read-later process as much as possible and document relevant posts for future reference.</p>

<p>Like most services now, Instapaper has a &#8220;Like&#8221; feature. If I read something that strikes a chord in me, I &#8220;Like&#8221; it. This is great from an archivist perspective but what else can I do with it? I don&#8217;t always have time to compose a Tweet to the author, to be honest I&#8217;d rather just open the next article. Besides, the reason I use a Kindle is because I don&#8217;t want to be distracted.</p>

<h2><a href="https://ifttt.com/recipes/58465" title="Like article in Instapaper, post a custom Tweet">☆ Instapaper ☆ > Twitter</a></h2>

<p>So I created this IFTTT recipe to post a Tweet once an Instapaper is &#8220;Liked&#8221;. I won&#8217;t go into how and why I chose to setup the recipe the way I did, I&#8217;ll leave that for another blog post <em>coming soon</em>. All I wanted to do is make sure I did something with that data, for me and the author.</p>

<p>I&#8217;m pretty sure Instapaper has a Tweet facility baked-in but I prefer to use IFTTT recipes to get a little more customization into that 140-character limit.</p>

<p>My ideal automated Tweet would have:</p>

<ol>
<li>Custom text</li>
<li>Article title</li>
<li>Article link</li>
<li>Author name</li>
<li>Twitter @ handle</li>
<li>Content related hashtags per post</li>
</ol>


<p>Using the Instapaper baked-in facility lets you do 2 and 3 easily enough, next up would be visiting the blog url and using a Tweet button and customizing the text, or you could just open up your nearest device and create exactly want you want.</p>

<p>I thought I might be able to at least get the author name from the Instapaper &#8220;Liked&#8221; RSS feed but apparently not, quite an odd omission for an online/offline read-later service. I had a crack at the Instapaper <a href="http://www.instapaper.com/publishers" title="Instapaper page for controling text parsing for your site with HTML">text parsing</a>, but I must admit <a href="http://gim.ie/FqsD" title="Dog flying a helicopter">I had no idea what I was doing</a>, please <a href="http://twitter.com/benjaminparry" title="Benjamin Parry on Twitter">Tweet me</a> if you can help me out at all.</p>

<p>So IFTTT can handle 1, 2 and 3 but it seems 4, 5 and 6 have to be hacked together somehow.</p>

<h2>A blogging framework for hackers.</h2>

<p>Enter <a href="http://octopress.org/" title="Octopress blogging platform homepage">Octopress</a>. It&#8217;s been a perfect excuse to get started with Github and chance for me to explore the author&#8217;s place in this workflow.</p>

<p>Seeing as the Instapaper RSS feed only includes title, link, pubDate and description I decided to include the majority of the Tweet details above in the title of each post. Here&#8217;s how I did that.</p>

<h3>Add author name and Twitter @ handle</h3>

<p>I tried a few different combinations of this before adding a site author in _config.yml</p>

<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>author: Benjamin Parry @benjaminparry</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<h3>Add content related hashtags per post</h3>

<p>I was already using categories so I now precede each entry with an escaped #</p>

<p><em>GOTCHA ~ this generates without spaces so looks slightly odd in the published urls</em></p>

<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>categories: 
</span><span class='line'>- &#35;Octopress&nbsp;
</span><span class='line'>- &#35;Instapaper&nbsp;
</span><span class='line'>- &#35;Twitter&nbsp;</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<h3>Put it all together in the page title</h3>

<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>&#123;&#37; if page.title &#37;&#125;&#123;&#123; page.title &#125;&#125; ~ &#123;&#37; endif &#37;&#125;&#123;&#37; if page.author &#37;&#125;&#123;&#123; page.author &#125;&#125;&#123;&#37; endif &#37;&#125; &#123;&#37; if page.categories &#37;&#125;&#123;&#123; page.categories &#125;&#125;&#123;&#37; else &#37;&#125;&#123;&#123; site.description &#125;&#125;&#123;&#37; endif &#37;&#125;</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<h3>What it looks like in a Tweet</h3>

<p><em>not tweeted yet</em></p>

<h2>Happy, Not Happy</h2>

<p>The moment I finally got this together and tested I got the email from IFTTT informing of the closure of some of the Twitter related recipe services. Luckily this recipe is safe as posting content <strong>to</strong> Twitter is allowed but posting <strong>Twitter&#8217;s</strong> content to another service is not. A lucky escape, for now, although it does break some of my custom workflow that I will need to re-think.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hello Octoworld]]></title>
    <link href="http://benjaminparry.github.com/blog/2012/07/26/title/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-26T10:45:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://benjaminparry.github.com/blog/2012/07/26/title</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;ve finally got my act together and setup an Octopress blog.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
