<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: &#35;bookmarking&nbsp; | Benjamin Parry]]></title>
  <link href="http://benjaminparry.github.com/blog/categories/-35-bookmarking-nbsp-/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://benjaminparry.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-09-26T22:24:41+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://benjaminparry.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Benjamin Parry]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Starcatching Supernova bookmarking]]></title>
    <link href="http://benjaminparry.github.com/blog/2012/09/24/starcatching-supernova-bookmarking/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-24T19:41:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://benjaminparry.github.com/blog/2012/09/24/starcatching-supernova-bookmarking</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>This is part of a talk I will be giving at <a href="http://2012.barcampbrighton.org/" title="BarCampBrighton 7 homepage">BarCampBrighton 7</a> <strong>My attempt at the perfect read-later workflow</strong></p></blockquote>

<p>I was one of the Delicious refugees of 2011 that ended up making a happy home at <a href="pinboard.in/" title="Social Bookmarking for Introverts">pinboard.in</a>. I was pretty rubbish at keeping up with tagging then and still pretty rubbish now, although Pinboard offer a superbly simple UI and cracking bookmarklet that makes light work adding new bookmarks and suggested tags.</p>

<p>Frank Chimero’s excellent talk <a href="http://2011.dconstruct.org/conference/frank-chimero" title="Frank Chimero’s Oh God, It’s Full of Stars audio from dConstruct 2011">Oh God, It’s Full of Stars</a> is a fascinating inward look at why we bookmark and what we do that data afterward. Ever since listening to it I've been concerned with mastering an automated workflow that adds as much useful sorting/retrieval data to those bookmarks, and, if possible, does something with it meaningful with it too.</p>

<h2>Case study: Twitter</h2>

<p>I favorite a hell of a lot of Tweets. Twitter don't provide a decent enough solution to filter them, something only <a href="http://faavorite.com/" title="Twitter favorite managing app">faavorite.com</a> does well. Pinboard has a baked-in Twitter sync that pulls in links from your favorite Tweets. Initially I enabled it but thought there was more data that could be squeezed into the bookmark.</p>

<h3>Putting the internet to work for me</h3>

<p><a href="https://ifttt.com/" title="IFTTT homepage">If This Then That</a> is an amazing service that bridges the API gap between online services like Pinboard and Twitter and turned out to provide me with exactly the right kind of customization I wanted over my Twitter bookmarks.</p>

<p>There's a few different reasons why I might want to favorite a Tweet:</p>

<ol>
<li>URL to interesting resource or article</li>
<li>Memorable or funny quote</li>
<li>Interesting conversation between 2 or more users</li>
</ol>


<p>So for an ideal bookmark entry it must have:</p>

<ol>
<li>URL included in the Tweet as the default bookmark URL</li>
<li>URL to the Tweet itself if the Tweet itself is the bookmark and the entire Tweet text</li>
<li>@ Twitter handle of the user</li>
</ol>


<p><em>As a bonus, related hashtags auto imported as tags</em></p>

<h3><a href="https://ifttt.com/recipes/58634" title="Favorite Tweet and add new Pinboard bookmark">☆ Twitter ☆ > Pinboard</a></h3>

<p>So I created a recipe that does just that, and more.</p>

<p>Currently, every time I favorite a Tweet the recipe is triggered and I get a bookmark that includes:</p>

<ol>
<li>Hyperlink to the first URL in the Tweet with it's page title</li>
<li>Copy of the entire Tweet in the description</li>
<li>Hyperlink to the Twitter user</li>
<li>Hyperlink to the Tweet status</li>
<li>Tagged with custom identifier for filtering all Twitter favorites -  ☆twitter☆</li>
<li>Tagged with user's @ Twitter handle for filtering</li>
</ol>


<p>This gives me a few options when coming back to retrieve a bookmarked URL, either I have a fair idea who's Tweeted it or what text was included in the Tweet, both of which can be easily filtered through Pinboard's powerful search.</p>

<p>I must admit pulling in hashtags as bookmark tags would be a huge advantage and unfortunately the URLs in the Tweet copy remain encrypted in Twitter's t.co style which is very frustrating.</p>

<p>Even more annoying is that IFTTT now has to shut off most of their Twitter services after Twitter announced their recent API re-write. It's a huge blow for a whole spectrum of users, one that might have <a href="https://join.app.net/" title="Developer focused, add-free social network">app.net</a> opening their doors wide. They already have IFTTT support so it just need that mass exodus like back in 2011.</p>

<h3>A galaxy of Likes</h3>

<p>The idea is to apply this method to every site that offers a favorite, Like or do-later operation, trying to squeeze as much additional data into the bookmark and improve the options for retrieval to close the loop.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
